We bury our sins, we wash them clean.
Mystic River is a thriller, crime, drama film directed by Clint Eastwood.
The lives of three men who were childhood friends are
shattered when one of them suffers a family tragedy.
Jimmy Markum, played by Sean Penn.
Dave Boyle, played by Tim Robbins.
Sean Devine, played by Kevin Bacon.
Whitey Powers, played by Laurence Fishburne.
Celeste Boyle, played by Marcia Gay Harden.
Annabeth Markum, played by Laura Linney.
Mystic River is a 2003 American neo-noir mystery crime drama film, directed and co-produced by Clint Eastwood, and
starring Sean Penn, Tim Robbins, Kevin Bacon, Laurence Fishburne, Marcia Gay Harden, and Laura Linney.
The screenplay, written by Brian Helgeland, was based
on the 2001 novel by Dennis Lehane.
It is the first film in which Eastwood was credited as composer of the score.
The film was produced by Village Roadshow Pictures, Malpaso Productions and NPV Entertainment, premiered at the
2003 Cannes Film Festival on May 23, 2003, and was released on October 15, 2003 by Warner Bros.
Pictures, and was a critical and commercial success.
Mystic River was nominated for six awards at the 76th Academy Awards, including Best
Picture, winning Best Actor for Penn, and Best Supporting Actor for Robbins.
The film explores themes of child abuse, sexual abuse, workers'
quarter, based on novel or book, loss of loved one.
The tone is mind_bending and emotional and intense.